Guide to the John Eugene Unterecker Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
John Eugene Unterecker Papers,
1961-1987
Unterecker, John Eugene, 1922-
53 linear ft.(ca. 50,000 items in 123 boxes and 3 file card boxes)
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079747
History
Author, poet, and professor of English at Columbia University from 1958-1974 (M.A. 1948; Ph.D. 1956).
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, documents, subject files, audiotapes, and printed materials. The collection covers all of Unterecker's professional and artistic interests: his research for Voyager, Approaches To The Twentieth Century Novel, Lawrence Durrell, as well as his correspondence with numerous academics, writers, and poets.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 12 series:
Series I: Cataloged Series
Series II: Arranged Material
Series III: Correspondence Files
Series IV: Manuscript and Book Production Files
Series V: Audiotaopes
Series VI: Audiotapes
Series VII: Miscellaneous manuscript re. Hart Crane
Series VIII: Correspondence files
Series IX: Poetry Manuscripts
Series X: Other Manuscripts
Series XI: Subject Files
Series XII: Transparencies
Subjects
Adams, Léonie, 1899-1988.; Barzun, Jacques, 1907-; Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979.; Bly, Robert.; Booth, Philip.; Boyle, Kay, 1902-1992.; Calisher, Hortense.; Clark, Tom, 1941-; Clemens, Cyril, 1902-; Corman, Cid.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Dahlberg, Edward, 1900-1977.; Diamond, David, 1915-2005.; Dickey, James.; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970.; Durrell, Lawrence.; Ehrenpreis, Irvin, 1920-; Feiffer, Jules.; Frank, Waldo David, 1889-1967.; Galpin, Alfred Maurice, 1901-1983.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Gunn, Thom.; Hall, Donald, 1928-; Heyen, William, 1940-; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; Highet, Gilbert, 1906-1978.; Ignatow, David, 1914-1997.; Justice, Donald Rodney, 1925-2004.; Kinnell, Galway, 1927-; Kizer, Carolyn.; Koch, Kenneth, 1925-2002.; Krementz, Jill.; Levertov, Denise, 1923-1997.; Levine, Philip, 1928-; Loewinsohn, Ron.; MacBeth, George.; Mack, Maynard, 1909-; Miles, Josephine, 1911-1985.; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972.; Moss, Howard, 1922-1987.; Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977.; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986.; Pack, Robert, 1929-; Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975.; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980.; Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974.; Snyder, Gary.; Stafford, Dorothy.; Stafford, William, 1914-1993.; Stallworthy, Jon.; Stout, Rex, 1886-1975.; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979.; Vogt, Gertrude.; Wakoski, Diane.; Wright, James Arlington, 1927-1980.; American poetry--20th century.; Criticism--History--20th century.; Critics--United States.; Literature--History and criticism.; Poetry, Modern--20th century.; Poets, American--20th century.; Clippings; Drafts (preliminary versions); Essays; Lectures; Manuscripts (for publication); Photoprints; Poems; Reviews (Criticism); Critics; Poets
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 1B-96. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
02/15/91 M-91-02-15 Unterecker Eatate Purchase
- Series I: Cataloged Series
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondnece
    - Adams, Leonie (Box 1)
    - Barzun, Jacques
    - Bishop, Elizabeth
    - Bly, Robert
    - Booth, Philip
    - Boyle, Kay
    - Calisher, Hortense
    - Clark, Tom
    - Clemens, Cyril
    - Corman, Cid
    - Cowley, Malcolm
    - Dahlberg, Edward
    - Diamond, David
    - Dickey, James
    - Dos Passos, John
    - Durrell, Lawrence
    - Ehrenpreis, Irvin
    - Feiffer, Jules
    - Frank, Waldo
    - Galpin, Alfred
    - Ginsberg, Allen
    - Gunn, Thom
    - Hall, Donald
    - Heyen, William
    - Hicks, Granville
    - Highet, Gilbert
    - Ignatow, David
    - Justice, Donald
    - Kinnell, Galway
    - Kirstein, Lincoln
    - Kizer, Carolyn
    - Koch, Kenneth
    - Levertov, Denise
    - Levine, Phillip
    - Loewinsohn, Ron
    - MacBeth, George (Box 1a)
    - Mack, Maynard
    - Miles, Josephine
    - Moore, Marianne
    - Moss, Howard
    - NIn, Anais
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia
    - Pack, Robert
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes
    - Porter, Katherine Anne
    - Ransom, John Crowe
    - Snyder, Gary
    - Stafford, Dorothy
    - Stafford, William
    - Stallworthy, Jon
    - Stout, Rex
    - Tate, Allan
    - Unterecker, John
    - Vogt, Gertrude
    - Wakoski, Diane
    - Wright, James
  - Subseries I.2: Manuscripts
    - Dickey, James
    - Unterecker, John
  - Subseries I.3: Documents
    - Portage County. Ohio. Probate Court
  - Subseries I.4: Art
    - Durrell, Lawrence
  - Subseries I.5: Photographs
    - Krementz, Jill
- Series II: Arranged Material
  - Unterecker, John Voyger notes, t.ms. and galley proofs (Box 1b)
  - Unterecker, John Correspondence, poroofs and manuscript of Approaches to the 20th Century Novel (Box 2)
  - Unterecker, John Manuscript on Durrell (Box 3)
  - Unterecker, John Forward to Nitchie's Marianne Moore Introduction to the Poetry
- Series III: Correspondence Files
  Correspondence Files relating to Voyager (Boxes 4-12) & Manuscript and Book Production Files (Boxes 13-23 and 3 file card boxes shelved after Box 23)
  - Addison, Bill (Box 4)
  - Aiken, Conrad
  - Aleavich, Anthony
  - Amamoto, Florence D.
  - American Philosophical Society Grant
  - Ames, Elizabeth
  - Anderson, Margaret
  - Anderson, Mrs. Sherwood
  - Arens, Egmont
  - Asch, Nathan
  - Babcock, Margaret
  - Baird, Raymond
  - Baker, Everetta
  - Baker, Howard
  - Baker, John
  - Baldwin, Charles
  - Baltzley
  - Banerjee, Bhola
  - Barr, George
  - Baughman, Richard
  - Bell, Jessie
  - Benedict, Harry
  - Benito, Mary Anne
  - Bennett, Emmett
  - Berthoff, Warner
  - Billington, David
  - Binet, Jean
  - Blackmur, R. P.
  - Bloch, Suzanne
  - Blond, Anthony
  - Bodenheim, Maxwell
  - Baken, Julia
  - Brenner, Anita
  - Breslow, Stephen P.
  - Breuer, Bessie
  - Brewster, James
  - Brien, Donald
  - Brooks, Charles
  - Brown, J. L.
  - Brown, Slater
  - Brown, Susan
  - Brown University
  - Brunner, E.
  - Bruno, Guido
  - Bruno, Michael
  - Bunn, Scott (Box 5)
  - Burdock, Eugene
  - Burke, Kenneth
  - Burnham, Scott
  - Burns, Edward
  - Butscher, Edward
  - Butterfield, R. W.
  - Bynner, Witter
  - Cady, Richard
  - Calder & Boyars, Publishers
  - Calhoun, Alice
  - Campbell, Roy
  - Candee, Harry
  - Caporicci, Antonio
  - Carnihan, Lucy
  - Carroll, Dudley
  - Casper, Leonard
  - Cate, Mrs. Russell
  - Chaffin, Tom
  - Chaikin, Lawrence
  - Charles, John W.Childs, James
  - Cirino, Linda
  - Clark, David
  - Clear, Val
  - Cleveland Research
  - Clevenger, Herbert
  - Coakley, William Leo
  - Collamore, H. D.
  - Colum, Padric and Mary
  - Columbia University News Release on NET Film
  - Columbia University Libraries
  - Columbia University Press
  - Congdon, Kirby
  - Connelly, Kathleen
  - Contemporary Literature
  - Conyers, Claude
  - Cooke, Leon
  - Cook, Steve
  - Cooper, William
  - Cordero, Luis
  - Corner, George
  - Coryn, Julie
  - Cosman, Anna
  - Council for Research in the Humanities
  - Cowley, Malcolm
  - Cowley, Peggy
  - Craggs, T. F.
  - Craib, Rod
  - Crane, Bess
  - Crane C. A.
  - Crane, Fredrica
  - Crane, Hart
  - Crane, Hart (Box 6)
  - Crane, Grace (Mother)
  - Crane, Grace (friend)
  - Crane, Ralph C.
  - Crane, H. W.
  - Crosby, Caresse
  - Cummings, E. E.
  - Cummings, Marion
  - Damon, S. Foster
  - Dawson, Hugh
  - Dawson, T.
  - DeFanti, Charles
  - Dehner, Dorothy
  - Dembo, L.
  - Dexter, Joseph
  - DiCapua, Michael
  - Dietz, Lorna
  - Dimen, S. T.
  - Doherty, Mary
  - Doreski, William
  - Drew, Fraser
  - Duke, Maurice
  - Durant, Regan
  - Elman, Bruce
  - English, Maurice
  - Erdelac, Joseph
  - Evans, Len
  - Evans, Walker
  - Evenitsky, Alfred
  - Falck, Colin
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux
  - Fernon, J. D.
  - Ferrer, ValŽrie
  - Filipe, Leon
  - Fetzer, Herman
  - Fichter, Robert
  - Fireman, Judith
  - Fitch, Robert
  - Fitzgerlad, Geoffrey
  - Fletcher, Herbert
  - Fletcher, James
  - Foley, Bernice
  - Ford, Ann
  - Ford, W. T.
  - Foster, Robert
  - Frank, Ralph
  - Frank, Waldo
  - Frease, Joseph
  - French, Windsor
  - Fussell, Charles
  - Galpin, Alfred (Box 7)
  - Gasparini, Len
  - George, John E
  - Giacomo, Manuel
  - Gibson, Roland
  - Glidzen, Alex
  - Giles, Paul
  - Ginther, Bert.
  - Giroux, Robert
  - Gotham Book Mart
  - Gover, Norman
  - Graham, James
  - Greulich, J. A.
  - Greenfield, Beth
  - Gross, Elbert
  - Grossberg, David
  - Grundel, Herbert
  - Grunberg, Solomon
  - Guggenheim Foundation
  - Hammond, Mac
  - Hanley, Helen
  - Hanson, Don
  - Harrell, Don W.
  - Harris, Charles
  - Harris, Elwin R.
  - Harrison, Thomas
  - Hartley, Marsden
  - Harvard Univ. Library
  - Harwell, Richard
  - Hatfield, Gordon
  - Heap, Jane
  - Hemley, Cecil
  - Hendrick, George
  - Henry, Jack
  - Herendeen, Warren
  - Hicks, John
  - Hirsch, Stefan
  - Herwaldt, David
  - Hirt, Mary
  - Hirschman, Jack
  - Hise, Bessie
  - Hobson, Richard
  - Hogg, Daniel
  - Holman, Talat
  - Holmes, Mildred
  - Horton, Philip
  - Howe, S. R.
  - Howard, Alan
  - Howard Nat.
  - Hubbard, Elbert
  - Hurd, C. K.
  - Hurlburt, Helen Hart
  - Hutchison, Collister
  - Hutchison, Hazel
  - Hutman, Norma Louise
  - Hutman, Norma
  - Hutson, Richard
  - Indiana University
  - Ingalls, Hunter
  - In Search of Hart Crane (film)
  - In Search of Hart Crane (film) (Box 8)
  - Ivans, Michael
  - Jackson, David
  - Jackson, Thomas F.
  - Jacobson, Liz
  - Jehenson, Yvonne
  - Johnson, Trebbe
  - Joseph, Helen Heiman
  - Josephson, Matthew
  - Kantor, J. R.
  - Kaplan, Phil.
  - Keegan, Francis R.
  - Kempf, Dr. Edward
  - Kenney, Sister Eileen
  - Kenney, Kay
  - Kerr, Jean
  - Kessinger, David
  - Kidder, Rushworth
  - King, Martin
  - Kingston, Roger
  - Kirsch, Randal
  - Kirk, George
  - Kizinski, Alexandra
  - Klein, Joseph
  - Kline, W. C.
  - Kling, Joseph
  - Kloucek, Jerome
  - Knox, George
  - Koki, Arthur
  - Kolko, Gabriel
  - Kramer, Aaron
  - Krapp, Philip
  - Kray, Elizabeth
  - Lachaise, Gaston
  - LaFrance, Marston
  - Langton, Jane
  - Laukhuff, Mrs. Richard
  - Laurent, Robert
  - Leary, Lewis
  - Linewell, George
  - Lescaze, George
  - Lescaze, William
  - Lewis, R. B. W.
  - Lewis, Richard
  - Lesis, S. W. Thomas
  - Lewis, Ward
  - Leyda, Jay
  - Library of Congress
  - Linneman, G.
  - Linneweaver, John
  - Livingston,.Art.
  - Livingston, Ralph
  - LLoyd, John
  - Lockwood Memorial Library
  - Loeb, Harold
  - Loehr, Bob
  - Lombardi, Tom.
  - Long, Robert Emmet
  - Lovecraft, H. P.
  - Loveman, Sam
  - Lowry, Tom
  - Loyola Univ. of Chicago
  - Lynch, Michael
  - Madden, Betty
  - Major, John
  - Maltby, Joe (Box 9)
  - McCaslin, Mrs. John White
  - McClelland, Pvt. Don.
  - McCullough, Sister Ann
  - MacCowan, Eugene
  - McHugh, Harley
  - McHugh, John
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - McSweeney, Kerry
  - Manfred, Ernest
  - Mann, Charles
  - Manzo, David
  - Marin, John
  - Marshall, Jon
  - Martin, Robert K.
  - Mayfield, John
  - Mazzella, Tony
  - Mersch, Dr. Arnold
  - Mexican Information (Tepoztlan)
  - Mihaila, Dorica
  - Milwaukee Public Library
  - Minns, Hervey
  - Miscellaneous
  - The Modernist
  - Moe, Henry Allen
  - Moody, Harriet
  - Moore, Ian
  - Moore, John G.
  - Moses, Lester
  - Munson, Gorham
  - Murphy, Francis
  - Murphy, Michael
  - Murphy, Russell
  - Museum of Modern Art
  - Mutch, George E.
  - Nadeau, Irene
  - The Nation
  - Nelson, Ernest
  - Neu, Mrs. Fred.
  - New American Library
  - Newberry Library
  - Newman, Charles
  - Nichols, Doug.
  - Nilson, Helge
  - Norman, Dorothy
  - Norvell, Blanche
  - Notes on a Poem by Hart Crane
  - Nuwer, Henry
  - O'Gorman, Ned
  - Ohioana Library Association
  - Ohio State University
  - Ohio State University Press
  - Olpin, Larryu
  - O'Neill, Eugene
  - Opffer, Emil
  - Oppenheimer, Mrs. Herbert
  - Ottaviano, Gioia
  - Parker, Donald
  - Parker Nancy
  - Parkinson, Tom
  - Patno, Stanley
  - Parkington, Michael
  - Patterson, Franklin
  - Paul, Sherman
  - Pack, Arlie
  - Peed, Mike
  - Pell, Arthur
  - Pelsinger, Ronald
  - Pemberton, Vivian
  - Peters, Wilhelmina
  - Petrie, Dennis
  - Phelps, Wylie
  - Piculin, Karl (Box 10)
  - Pigala, Thom
  - Plumb, Mrs. Robert
  - Pohl, Frederick
  - Pollard, Thomas
  - Pondram, Cyrena
  - Porter, Fairfield
  - Porter, Ray
  - Pound, Ezra
  - Preston, John
  - Princeton Univ. Press
  - Quinlan, Wayne
  - Quinn, Vincent
  - Raymond, Mrs. G. H.
  - Read, Dennis
  - Reed, Dennis
  - Reed, Perry
  - Regier, Bill
  - Rendell, Marion
  - Rhinehart, Mrs. Susan
  - Ridgley, Joe
  - Riordan, Maurice
  - Rixson, Eleanor
  - Robbins, Wendy
  - Rosenfeld, Paul
  - Rotella, Guy
  - Routledge and Kegan Paul
  - Ravenna and Kent
  - Runden, John
  - Rychtarik, Richard
  - Salamo, Michael J.
  - Salzberg, Karen
  - Sarot, Ellin
  - Schimmel, Harold
  - Schleifer, B.
  - Schmitt, Carl
  - Schneider, Harold
  - Schneider, Isador
  - Schorb, Patricia
  - Schwab, Arnold
  - Schwartz, Alan
  - Schwartz, Joseph
  - Scott, Ida
  - Scriggs, Charles
  - Seldes, Marian
  - Seluzicki, Charles
  - Swanee Review
  - Shalit, Gene
  - Sheaffer, Louis
  - Sheehy, Eugene
  - Sheffield, Margaret
  - Shipps, Anthony
  - Silver, Roger
  - Simon, Marc
  - Simmonds, Harry
  - Simpson, Leslie
  - Simpson, Lewis P.
  - Simpson, Sally
  - Siqueiros, David
  - Smith, Elizabeth
  - Smith, Harrison
  - Snyder, Kathleen
  - Sloan (Mrs. Josephine Sloan Hawkins)
  - Sloane, Wellington
  - Slusser, Robert M.
  - Smith, James
  - Smith, Ware
  - Socin, Jay
  - Solomon, Hyde
  - Solon, Israel
  - Sommer, Ray
  - Sommer, William
  - Sommer, William Jr.
  - Sorenson, Rexford
  - Soules, Jack A.
  - Spinucci, Pietro
  - Spears, Monroe
  - Klein, Arthur Luce
  - Spratling, William (Box 11)
  - Sprinchorn, Carl
  - Stanford, Donald
  - Stanko, Stan
  - Stansky, Peter
  - Steinberg, Jerry
  - Steinhout, Mrs. C. M.
  - Stella, Joseph
  - Stewart, Robert E.
  - Straus, Roger
  - Strempek, L.
  - Sullivan, Charles
  - Sure, E.
  - Swallow, Alan
  - Swetland, David
  - Swetland, Frederick
  - Tarn, Nathanial
  - Tate, Allen
  - Tate, Caroline Gordon
  - Thayer, Scofield
  - Thompson, Bobby
  - Thompson, J. Walter Agency
  - Todd, Leonard
  - Toomer, Jean
  - Tipka, Donald
  - Trachtenberg, Alan
  - Trebbe, Gail
  - True, Lynn
  - Turbyfill, Mark
  - Turkle, Pauline
  - Underwood, Wilbur
  - University of Buffalo
  - University of Chicago Library
  - University of Illinois Press
  - University of Texas
  - University of Virginia
  - Unterecker, John
  - Uroff, Margaret
  - Varney, John
  - Vendler, Helen
  - Voelcker, Hunce
  - Von Wiegand, Charmion (Box 12)
  - Wagner, Bernard
  - Waldhorn
  - Walter, David
  - Walton, Eda Lou
  - Weber, Brom
  - Weber, Larry
  - Wepman, Dennis
  - Wheat, Linda
  - Whisler, Glen
  - Whiteside, George
  - Whidney, W. A.
  - Wiederrecht, Ann
  - Wiggins, Henry
  - Williams, Mrs. Loring
  - Williams, William Carlos
  - Willingham, John R.
  - Winer, Joseph
  - Winters, Yvor
  - Wise, Herbert
  - Withers, Terrance
  - Woodcock, Mrs. David
  - Woodrong, Carl
  - Wortham, Thomas
  - Wright, Margaret
  - Wright, William
  - Yale University Library
  - Yanella, Phil
  - Zabel, Morton
  - Zetterstrom, B.
  - Zell, Lee H.
  - Zingler, Gilberta
  - Zinsser, Hans
  - Zorach, William
  - Zucher, Roger
- Series IV: Manuscript and Book Production Files
  - Undated or ambiguous date letter file (Box 13)
  - Early letter file
  - Akron Information
  - Unterecker, John "A Piece of Pure Invention"
  - Notes on Columbia correspondence
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux
  - Giles, Paul "The Contents of The Bridge
  - Hart Crane lectures (Box 13a)
  - Hart Crane walk (2 maps)
  - Horizon article discussion
  - In Search of Heart Crane
    [notes and drafts, publicity, correspondence, reviews, etc]
  - "Introduction to the Poetry of Hart Crane."
  - Miscellaneous Crane materials
  - Hart Crane: addresses of correspondents
  - Notes on Crane poems
  - "The Poems of Hart Crane." t.ms.
  - Schultz, Susan M. "Hart Crane's Divided Voice" (Box 13b)
  - Voelcker, Hunce "Bridge"
  - Voyager
    [draft of acknowledgements; book distribution; errata, front matter; correcpondence; school records, etc]
  - Hart Crane Broadcast on WBAI (Box 14)
  - Hart Crane photographs
  - Hart Crane drawings and photographs held by Richard Rychtarik
  - Acknowlegements.
  - In Search of Hart Crane
    [darfts of script; library sequence; passages from Crane's books; etc]
  - Voyager
    [Material deleted from final draft; uncut and unrevised final draft; original revised typescript.]
  - Voyager (Box 15)
    [Original revised typescript, cont]
  - Original galley pages 148-196
  - "The Architecture of The Bridge" (carbon of talk)
  - Review for Yale Review
  - "Notes on a poem by Hart Crane"
- Series V: Audiotaopes
  - "Documentary: The Last Days of Hart Crane" (Box 15a)
    [2 copies]
  - "Greitzer: 2nd interview"
  - T. S. Eliot "Invitation to Learning"
  - "Oscar Bernstein, July 1962"
  - "Poems of Hart Crane for Women's Chorus and Band"
  - "Poetry of Hart Crane: John Unterecker"
  - "Sue Brown, Peggy Baird"
- Series VI: Audiotapes
  - 4 untitled tapes (Box 15b)
  - "Yeats Anthology Interview"
  - Voyager (Box Boxes 16-23)
  - Typescript (1) (Box 16)
  - Typescript (2) (Box 17)
  - Typescript carbon (1) (Box 18)
  - Typescript carbon (2) (Box 19)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous manuscript re. Hart Crane
  - Galley proofs (corrected) (Box 20)
  - Galley proofs (1) (Box 21)
  - Galley proofs (2) (Box 22)
  - Galley proofs (3) (Box 23)
  - Three boxes containing card files: 1. Names and titles; 2. Chapter notes, 1-370; 3. Chapter notes, 371-end and Bibliography.
- Series VIII: Correspondence files
  - Abrahams, Roger (TEPCO) (Box 1)
  - Abramson, Charles A.
  - Academy of American Poets
  - Academy of American Poets Affiliated Societies
  - Ackerson, Duane
  - Adams, Edward
  - Adams, Joseph
  - Adams, John
  - Adams, Phoebe
  - Addabbo, Joseph
  - Adelman, Gary
  - Adelson, Dorothy
  - Aertker, Rowland
  - Akaka, Jeffrey
  - Akamino, Sheri mae
  - Akiko
  - Akins, Terese
  - Alexander, Anne
  - Alford, Shelley
  - Allen, Bill
  - Allen, Don Camero
  - Allen, Donald
  - Allen, James
  - Allen, Rosemary
  - Allentuck, Marcia
  - Allsup, Jim
  - Alphonso-Karkala, John
  - Alspach, Russel
  - Altamira
  - Altizer, Nell -- poet (Box 2)
  - American Book Review
  - American Committee for Irish Studies
  - American Literary Abstracts
  - American Scholar
  - American Way
  - Ames, Elizabeth
  - Amirthanayagam, Guy
  - Among, Michael
  - Anderson, Chet -- critic
  - Anderson, Erland -- poet
  - Anderson, George
  - Anderson, Howie
  - Anderson, Jane
  - Anderson, Tulle
  - Andre, Michael
  - Anglo-Welsh Review
  - Angoff, Charles
  - Antaeus -- Ecco Press
  - Antioch Review
  - Appel, Allan
  - Appleton, Bill
  - Aquino, Mrs. Betty
  - Arbin, Diana
  - Arena, Electa
  - Arizona Quarterly (Box 3)
  - Ark River Review
  - Armisted, Myrtle
  - Arnold, Karen
  - Aroksaar, Richard
  - Artim, A.R.
  - Arts in Ireland, The
  - Ash, Niema
  - Ashburn, John
  - Ashton, Thomas
  - Asnes, Fred
  - Associated University Presses
  - Atkinson, Jim
  - Atlantic Monthly
  - Atlantic Monthly Press
  - Attanasio, Al -- novelist
  - Audit
  - Auerbach
  - Augustine, Sandra
  - Aushman, Jimmie
  - Austin, John
  - Australia
  - Australian-American Education Foundation
  - Avent, Glynda
  - Aw, Arthur
  - Axtmann, Annette
  - Bachilegga, Christina
  - Baciu, Stefan
  - Bagley, Bryan
  - Bair, Dee -- Beckett's biographer
  - Balaban, John
  - Balakiau, Anna
  - Bales, Kent
  - Balfoort, Pat
  - Balfour, Yvanna
  - Banton, Frank
  - Barber, C.L. -- critic
  - Barnard, Harry
  - Barnard Poetry Contest
  - Barnett, Linda
  - Barquist, Claudia
  - Barrett, H.P.
  - Bass, Jon
  - Bassoff, Bruce
  - Batchellor, Mrs. Joseph
  - Bauer, Richard (Box 4)
  - Baum, Jean
  - Bauslog
  - Baysa, Fred
  - Beale, Ms. Roberta
  - Beams, David
  - Begley, Bryan
  - Behen, Denis
  - Beja, Morris
  - Bell, Marvin -- poet
  - Bellingham Review
  - Beloit Poetry Journal
  - Benedict, John
  - Benedict, Michael
  - Benn, Harry
  - Benstock, Bernie
  - Berge, Carol
  - Berger, Leon
  - Berger, Seymour
  - Bernhardt, William F.
  - Bernikow, Louise
  - Bernstein, Suzy
  - Berry, Mrs. Bette
  - Berryman, John -- teaching materials
  - Bertholf, Robert
  - Besher, Ruby
  - Beyers, Robert
  - Bidwell, Bruce
  - Bidwell, Dan
  - Birchman, Edward
  - Bird, Betty
  - Bird Effort
  - Bits Press
  - Blaber, Ron
  - Blake, Gail
  - Blaich, Beryl
  - Blasdel, Christopher
  - Bliss, Corinne
  - Blond, Anthony
  - Blossom, Laurel
  - Blueline
  - Bly, Robert
  - Boatright, Jim
  - Boatwright, Philip -- editor (Box 5)
  - Bob, Theone
  - Bochner, Jay and Sally
  - Bock, Martin
  - Bode, Carl
  - Bodenner, Becky
  - Bogdan, Herman
  - Bogen, Nancy
  - Bolton, Felicity
  - Borenstein, Emily
  - Borich, Michael
  - Bouslog, Charles
  - Bowker Company
  - Bowman, Peter
  - Bowman, Sylvia
  - Boyd, Megan
  - Boyers, Bob -- editor, Salmagundi
  - Boyland, Sylvia M.
  - Bradley, Benjamin
  - Bradley, Sam
  - Braha, Elliot
  - Brahms, Jonathan
  - Bransten, John
  - Breslow, Stephen
  - Bresner, Jay
  - Bridges, Marybeth
  - Brigham, James
  - Brigham, Kay
  - Briscoe, Donald
  - Britton, Donald
  - Broadwell, Edward
  - Brock, Richard
  - Bromberg, Draisin
  - Brooks, Steve
  - Brophey, James
  - Brose, Maria
  - Brown, Homer
  - Browne, Michael Dennis -- poet
  - Bruchal, Joseph
  - Brustein, Robert
  - Bryer, Jack
  - Buck, Mr. and Mrs.
  - Buckley, Dave
  - Buckley, Ralph H.
  - Buckley, Winifred
  - Bucknell University Press
  - Buell, Albert
  - Buffalo, University of
  - Bullock, Mrs. Hugh
  - Burdett, Marge
  - Burditt, Mary
  - Burgess, Charles
  - Burgess, Lowrey
  - Burke, Helen
  - Burke, Susie
  - Burke, Tim
  - Burroughs, William -- writer
  - Byons, Kevin
  - Byrne, Peggy
  - Cabacungan, Bernie
  - Cabacungan, Darrell
  - Cabral, Kathleen
  - Cades, Russell
  - Caedmon Records
  - Chana, Ronnie
  - CAIM
  - Callow, Noel
  - Cambridge University Press
  - Cammarota, Richard
  - Canady, Phil
  - Canary, Robert
  - Canfield, Cass -- editor
  - Caparoso, Fred
  - Card, James
  - Cardwell, Cheryl
  - Carens, Jim
  - Carleton Miscellany
  - Carolina Israelite
  - Carolina Quarterly
  - Carr, Elizabeth
  - Carson, Meredith
  - Cartier, Joy
  - Cartwright, Michael
  - Caryl, Warren
  - Casalece, Sal
  - Casarella, Edmond
  - Casey, Dan
  - Cassell, Coralie
  - Castronoud, David
  - Cattoner, Joan
  - Cattoner, Joanna
  - Causey, Lorraine
  - Cavanaugh, Phil
  - Cave Art
  - CEA Critic
  - Cedering, Siv
  - Ceravolo, Joseph
  - Cerf, Bennett
  - Chadha, Vijay
  - Chadwick, Joseph -- Yeats critic
  - Chaffin, Tom
  - Chaikin, Larry
  - Champaign-Urbana Courier
  - Champon, Ellen
  - Chang, Doreen
  - Chang, Laban
  - Charlot, Candace
  - Charlot, John
  - Chatfield, Hale
  - Chatterjee, Visvanath
  - Chelsea Review
  - Cherry, Elaine
  - Chessid, Herman
  - Chicago Review
  - Chock, Eric -- poet
  - Choi, Byong-Hyon
  - Chong, Wah
  - Christy, Lawrence
  - Chun, Herbert
  - Chung, Chong-wha
  - Ciardi, John
  - Cimarron Review
  - Cincinnati, University of
  - Circas, John
  - City College -- Assignments, Jr.
  - City College Literary Society
  - City College Phone Number
  - Claire, William
  - Clancy, May
  - Claremon, Neil
  - Clark, David -- Yeats critic
  - Clark, L.D.
  - Clark, W.R.
  - Clarke, Brenna
  - Clarke, Gilliam -- Welsh poet
  - Clarke, Jim
  - Clarke, Ray
  - Clay, John W.
  - Claydon, Sheila (Box 9)
  - Clayton, Stewart
  - Claytor, David L.
  - Cleary, Jim
  - Cleveland State University
  - Clifford, James
  - Cloud, Jess
  - Coad, Kermit
  - Coatsworth, Elizabeth
  - Cobb, Stephen